We had made it to France.
We knew the end of our journey was near, and our excitement grew each day.
The last few weeks had changed us; we were now stronger, fitter, more adventurous in our flight.
We particularly enjoyed following coastlines where we could catch the best winds to glide over the long beaches of Brittany.
That’s why, at first, we didn’t worry when the wind started to rise that evening.
We had been flying for about an hour. The moon was full and the waves were reflecting her light like a distorted mirror.
The wind was getting stronger, but it was all a game to us.
“You’re losing your balance, Bird!” Shouted Banjoko.
“You wish”, I laughed, “I’ll race you to the end of that cape!”
I spread my wings and accelerated. I could hear the wind whistling in my ears and my friend calling me, trying to catch up. I raced further.
Suddenly, a huge cloud covered the moon and darkness fell upon us.
It started to rain heavily. Thunder was rumbling, and I couldn’t hear Banjoko anymore.
I looked back, but he was nowhere to be seen.
Violent gusts of wind made it hard to keep my balance. It was so dark that I couldn’t see anything.
Then I heard my friend’s voice being carried by the storm.
“Mawusi!” He never called me by my name. That’s how I knew how scared he was.
Huge hailstones fell all around us, one hit my left wing, making me lose my balance.
And then, I saw a light. A huge light, brighter than the sun, right in the middle of the night.
“Am I dead?” I wondered.
As I flew towards it, Nunyati’s voice echoed in my head.
“Follow the stars, Mawusi. They are the only lights you can trust. Fly away from all the others, as fast as you can.”
I closed my eyes and called my friend.
“Let’s land”, I screamed. I don’t think he heard me.
I tried to make it to the ground, battling against the storm. I missed my landing and crashed on the beach.
I dragged my battered body to a small cavity between rocks and decided to wait there.
I waited all night, the wind howling around me. I was terrified.
In the morning, the storm finally calmed down and I managed to go out.
In front of me stood a huge concrete tower, a red and white striped giant reaching for the sky.
I looked at it in awe, I had never seen anything like it before.
And that’s when I noticed the tiny green shape curled up at the bottom, lifeless.
My friend.
Banjoko.